bodyforlife.com 2018-10-29

# Privacy Policy | Abbott Nutrition

## Abbott Nutrition Privacy Policy - US Residents only

This Policy applies to residents of the United States.If you are a resident of another country, please click here for [applicable information](http://www.abbott.com/global-sites.html). This Privacy Policy explains how Abbott handles information that is collected from or about you or your device on websites and mobile applications controlled by Abbott Laboratories (including its subsidiaries and affiliates, in this case, Abbott Nutrition) which link to this Privacy Policy (referred to as “Abbott Nutrition websites”). This Privacy Policy does not apply to information collected from you offline, to Abbott websites that do not link to this Privacy Policy, to residents of countries other than the United States, or to third-party websites to which Abbott Nutrition websites may link. Your use of Abbott Nutrition websites which link to this Privacy Policy is subject to this Privacy Policy and the [Terms of Use](http://www.abbott.com/online-terms-and-conditions.html).

Please read this Privacy Policy before using Abbott Nutrition websites or submitting personal information to us.

## How does this Privacy Policy define “personal information”?

“Personal information” means information that identifies you or could reasonably be used to identify you and which is submitted to and/or collected by Abbott Nutrition websites and maintained by Abbott in an accessible form. Examples of personal information include your name, your postal address and your telephone number.

## What information does Abbott collect online?

Abbott collects information in a few different ways:

  * **_Personal Information You Submit or Give Us Permission to Obtain._** Abbott collects personal information that you enter into data fields on Abbott Web sites. For example, you may submit your name, postal address, e-mail address, and/or other information in order to receive information about various subjects, register for Abbott programs, contact Abbott customer service, or respond to Abbott surveys. If you’re accessing Abbott Web sites on your mobile device, you may also choose to provide us with location data. To protect your privacy, you should not provide Abbott with any information that is not specifically requested. 

You may also give us permission to access certain personal information maintained by other service providers. For example, you may link your Facebook or Google account to Abbott, which allows us to obtain information from those accounts (such as your friends or contacts). The information we obtain from these services often depends on your settings or the applicable provider's privacy policies, so please check these policies before granting us access. You agree that we are not responsible for any acts or omissions by these social media service providers. If you give us permission to access this information, we will use it for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. 

  *   

  * **_Passive Collection of Information_** . Abbott may collect information about your visits to Abbott Nutrition websites without you actively submitting such information. This information can make your use of Abbott Nutrition websites easier and more meaningful by allowing Abbott to provide better service, customize sites based on consumer preferences, compile statistics, provide you with more relevant advertisements, analyze trends, and otherwise administer and improve Abbott Nutrition websites. As discussed in the “How do Abbott and its partners use cookies for advertising?” section below, such information may also be collected by Abbott’s advertising vendors and other partners. Here are some of the types of information collected when visiting Abbott Nutrition websites: 
    * _**Log data**_ . When you use Abbott Nutrition websites, our servers automatically record information (“log data”), including information that your browser sends whenever you visit an Abbott Nutrition Website or your mobile app sends when you’re using it. This log data may include information such as your Internet Protocol address, the address of the webpages you visited that had Abbott Nutrition website features, browser type and settings, the date and time of your request, how you used Abbott Nutrition websites, and cookie data. 
    * _**Cookie data**_ . Depending on how you’re accessing Abbott Nutrition websites, we and our approved partners may use “cookies” (a small text file sent by your computer each time you visit our sites, unique to your Abbott account or your browser) or similar technologies, to record log data. When we use cookies, we may use “session” cookies (that last until you close your browser) or “persistent” cookies (that last until you and/or your browser delete them). For example, we may use cookies to remember your personal preferences, such as sections of that Web site that you visit frequently, your user ID, or other settings so you don’t have to set them up every time you visit Abbott Nutrition websites. Some of the cookies we use are associated with your Abbott account (including personal information about you, such as the email address you gave us), and other cookies are not. Please see the “How do Abbott and its partners use cookies for advertising?” section below for more information. 
    * _**Social Media Plugins and Data**_ . In addition, Abbott Nutrition websites may use social media plugins (e.g., the Facebook "Like" button, '"Share to Twitter"' button) to enable you to easily share information with others. When you visit Abbott Nutrition websites, the operator of the social plugin can place a cookie on your computer, enabling that operator to recognize individuals who have previously visited our Abbott Nutrition websites. If you are logged into the social media website (e.g., Facebook, Twitter, Google+) while browsing on Abbott Nutrition websites, the social plugins allow that social media website to receive information that you have visited Abbott Nutrition Web sites. The social plugins also allow the social media website to share information about your activities on Abbott Nutrition websites with other users of their social media website. For example, Facebook Social Plugins allows Facebook to show your Likes and comments on our pages to your Facebook friends. Facebook Social Plugins also allow you to see your friends' Facebook activity on Abbott Nutrition websites. Abbott does not control any of the content from the social media plugins. For more information about social plugins from other social media websites you should refer to those sites' privacy and data sharing statements. 
    * _**Device information**_ . In addition to log data, we may also collect information about the device you’re using to access Abbott Nutrition websites, including what type of device it is, what operating system you’re using, device settings, unique device identifiers, and crash data. Whether we collect some or all of this information often depends on what type of device you’re using and its settings. For example, different types of information are available depending on whether you’re using a Mac or a PC, or an iPhone or an Android phone. To learn more about what information your device may make available to us, please also check the policies of your device manufacturer or software provider. 
  * _**Information Provided by Abbott Partners**_ . Our advertising vendors and other partners may share with Abbott the information they collect. For example, our advertising vendors may share information with us regarding Abbott ads on websites or applications where such ads run to measure and/or improve those ads. Abbott may receive this information, which may include information like whether clicks on ads led to purchases or a list of criteria to use in targeting ads. 

## In what circumstances might Abbott use personal information?

Abbott will use the personal information you provide through Abbott Nutrition websites to respond to your questions and to provide you with efficient customer service.

Abbott may also use information collected from you through your use of Abbott Nutrition websites for other legitimate business purposes, such as to:

  * Provide our products and services to you and make them better, and to develop new products and services.
  * Send you notices and information regarding Abbott’s products or services, including notifying you about special promotions.
  * Invite you to participate in surveys about our products or services.
  * Furnish and maintain Abbott Nutrition websites.
  * Protect Abbott and our users.
  * Secure our network and Abbott Nutrition websites.

Abbott may also use information collected from you or about you to offer you customized content, including to:

  * Recognize new or past visitors to Abbott Nutrition websites.
  * Remember your personal preferences.
  * Show you more relevant and meaningful advertisements.
  * Better understand the interests of our customers and visitors to Abbott Nutrition websites.
  * Conduct research and analyze the use of our Abbott Nutrition Web sites, products, services, and advertisements.

In addition, some of our applications and mobile-optimized sites may have location-based features. To deliver these features, we may collect and use location data provided by your mobile device if you give us permission. For example, we may offer shopping features that allow you to get information about local merchants. Location information will be collected solely to deliver the requested feature, and it will not be further retained or stored by Abbott. By using such applications, you consent to the collection and use of your mobile device location data for purposes of delivering these location-based features.

## How do Abbott and its partners use cookies for advertising?

Abbott uses common tools, such as cookies and similar technologies (discussed in the _“What information does Abbott collect online?”_ section above), to collect information about users when they access Abbott Nutrition websites for purposes of enhancing their online experience and delivering more meaningful advertisements. Like many companies, Abbott may also utilize third party advertising vendors and other partners to collect this information.

One way in which we deliver more meaningful advertisements is through a common form of online advertising known as “retargeting” or “remarketing.” Retargeting works by serving ads on one site based on an individual’s online activities on a different, unrelated site. For example, if you look at Similac® products on an Abbott Nutrition website, you may later see an advertisement for Similac® products when you visit third party sites. To do this, Abbott or its advertising vendors may use a device ID, cookie, or similar technology placed by Abbott or the advertising vendor when you visit Abbott Nutrition websites or third party websites or apps. The placing of these cookies or other technologies on your device may enable you to be identified across multiple websites and you should consult the privacy policies of our advertising vendors to understand how they collect and use your data.

Your ability to control the use of tracking tools such as cookies and to opt-out of retargeting activities is described in the _“What choices do I have about how Abbott collects and uses information about me?”_ section below.

## Does Abbott consolidate personal information?

Abbott may combine the personal information that you provide to us on one Abbott Nutrition website with the personal information provided by you on other Abbott Nutrition website. Abbott may also combine personal information that you provide to us online with our offline records as well as records provided by third parties. We use this consolidated information to help us better design Abbott websites and Abbott products, to communicate information to you, to enhance our marketing and research activities, and to facilitate the other business functions described in the _“In what circumstances might Abbott use information?”_ section above.

## What choices do I have about how Abbott collects and uses information about me?

You may always limit the amount and type of personal information that Abbott receives about you by choosing not to enter any personal information into forms or data fields on Abbott Nutrition websites. Some of our online services can only be provided to you if you provide us with appropriate personal information. Other parts of Abbott Nutrition websites may ask whether you wish to opt out or opt into our contact lists for offers, promotions and additional services that may be of interest to you.

You may also be provided with preference questions or preference boxes allowing you to indicate that you do not want Abbott Nutrition websites to use tracking technologies, such as cookies, to “remember” your information on return visits, such as user IDs or mailing addresses. In addition, you can control the use of tracking tools and limit retargeting activities as follows:

  * _**Controlling Tracking Tools.**_ Most web browsers have an option for turning off the cookie feature, which will prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, as well as (depending on the sophistication of your browser software) allowing you to decide on acceptance of each new cookie in a variety of ways. Get more [information](https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=http-3A__www.allaboutcookies.org_&d=BQMFAg&c=jqQLr8Vjrh9vQZQBMH8t0g&r=7YfLCMLddLU8IfN5M9XNAN827D7Li3tl_fByy0FYiYk&m=nxlY-Nkr0Z-BMmswWFguvR7Fo_AvfQ0aH2b13n5ACbw&s=AFBlJWpDL3hwC1bxinL922g4MU0XEvuRlGCuhH68s1Q&e=) about [cookies](https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=http-3A__www.adobe.com_devnet_security.html&d=BQMFAg&c=jqQLr8Vjrh9vQZQBMH8t0g&r=7YfLCMLddLU8IfN5M9XNAN827D7Li3tl_fByy0FYiYk&m=nxlY-Nkr0Z-BMmswWFguvR7Fo_AvfQ0aH2b13n5ACbw&s=WFiALhu3cttAVRDK0yUWgr71BngemB10DeUiwFfJPRE&e=) . You can also [control flash cookies](https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=http-3A__www.macromedia.com_support_documentation_en_flashplayer_help_settings-5Fmanager07.html&d=BQMFAg&c=jqQLr8Vjrh9vQZQBMH8t0g&r=7YfLCMLddLU8IfN5M9XNAN827D7Li3tl_fByy0FYiYk&m=nxlY-Nkr0Z-BMmswWFguvR7Fo_AvfQ0aH2b13n5ACbw&s=J_DUD9g9V2b02gVeXJByt6OSY6hzlX0ql_EVWTAwf7w&e=) which we may use on certain Abbott Nutrition websites from time to time. Why? Because flash cookies cannot be controlled through your browser settings. 
  * **_Opting-Out of Retargeting Activities._** The Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising program provides consumers with the ability to [opt-out](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/#completed) of having their online behavior recorded and used for advertising purposes.click here to [opt out](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) of having your online behavior collected for advertising purposes and receiving behavioral advertisements from our advertising partners, including retargeting advertisements. Choices you make are both browser and device-specific. Also, certain versions of the iOS operating system permit you to “Limit Ad Tracking” in the system settings, and certain versions of the Android operating system allow you to “Opt out of Interest-Based Ads” in the system settings. Options you select are browser and device specific. 
  * _**Abbott Do Not Track Policy** . _ Abbott honors the AdChoice Do Not Track (“DNT”) signals. Please be aware that limiting the ability of websites to set cookies, however, may worsen your overall user experience, and in some cases the sites will not work properly without cookies, local storage and similar technologies. 

## Who will have access to personal information about me?

Personal information can be accessed by a restricted number of Abbott employees, by certain companies with which Abbott may conduct joint programs, and by individuals and entities with whom Abbott contracts to carry out business activities for Abbott. We train our employees about the importance of privacy and how to handle and manage customer data appropriately and securely. Also, it is Abbott’s practice to notify you if you are registering for a program which is conducted in conjunction with another company that may require access to your personal information. In addition, Abbott’s practice is to require its contractors to keep your personal information confidential and to use personal information only to perform functions for Abbott.

## Does Abbott share personal information with third parties?

As a general rule, Abbott does not share your personal information with third parties, unless it is necessary to conduct a joint program or to carry out a program or activity through a contractor. Where required by law, Abbott will not disclose your personal information to third parties for those third parties’ marketing purposes, unless you have been provided with an opportunity to opt into or opt out of this disclosure. However, if Abbott sells one of its product lines or divisions, your personal information may be transferred to the buyer so that the buyer can continue to provide you with information and services. If Abbott provides your personal information to individuals and entities which assist us with our business activities, it is Abbott’s practice to require those individuals and entities to keep your personal information confidential and to use your personal information only to perform functions for Abbott. Abbott reserves the right to disclose your personal information to respond to authorized information requests from government authorities, to address national security situations, or when otherwise required by applicable law.

## How does Abbott secure personal information?

It is Abbott’s practice to secure each webpage that collects personal information; however, the confidentiality of personal information transmitted over the Internet cannot be guaranteed. We urge you to exercise caution when transmitting personal information over the Internet, especially personal information related to your health. Abbott cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will not gain access to your personal information; therefore, when submitting personal information to Abbott Nutrition websites, you must weigh both the benefits and the risks. In addition, Abbott Nutrition websites covered by this Privacy Policy will display a warning whenever you link to a Web site that is not controlled by Abbott or subject to an Abbott privacy policy; you should check the privacy policies of such third-party Web sites before submitting personal information.

Abbott has policies, which provide for the proper use and protection of Social Security numbers obtained in the course of doing business with Abbott. Abbott’s policies require that Social Security numbers be appropriately secured to avoid loss, misuse or unauthorized access of Social Security numbers. Unlike this Privacy Policy, which applies only to on-line personal information, Abbott’s policies governing Social Security numbers apply to both online and offline collection and use of Social Security numbers.

## How does Abbott protect the privacy of children?

Abbott does not knowingly collect or use any personal information from children (we define “children” as minors younger than 13) on Abbott Nutrition websites. We do not knowingly allow children to order our products, communicate with us, or use any of our online services. If you are a parent and become aware that your child has provided us with information, please contact us using one of the methods specified below, and we will work with you to address this issue.

## How may I correct personal information or delete it from current customer records?

You may request to remove your personal information from our current customer records or to amend your personal information. Please notify us of your wishes by contacting us in one of the ways specified below. For our record keeping purposes, we will retain certain personal information you submit in conjunction with commercial transactions.

## How can I contact Abbott?

If you have questions about the use, amendment, or deletion of personal information that you have provided to us, or if you would like to opt out of future communications from an Abbott business or a particular Abbott program, please contact us by clicking on the “Contact Us” link on the website you are visiting or by e-mailing us at webmaster@abbott.com. Alternatively, you may send a letter to the following address:

Abbott Laboratories   
Attention: Public Affairs, Department 383   
100 Abbott Park Road   
Abbott Park, IL 60064-6048

In all communications to Abbott, please include the email address used for registration (if applicable), the website address or he specific Abbott program to which you provided personal information (e.g. Abbott.com, Similac.com, etc.), and a detailed explanation of your request. If you would like to delete or amend your personal information and are contacting us by email, please put “Deletion Request” or “Amendment Request”, as applicable, in the subject line of the e-mail. We will do our best to respond to all reasonable requests in a timely manner.

## How will I know whether Abbott has updated this policy?

Abbott reserves the right to amend this Privacy Policy without prior notice to reflect technological advancements, legal and regulatory changes and good business practices. If Abbott changes its privacy practices, a new Privacy Policy will reflect those changes and the effective date of the revised Privacy Policy will be set forth in this paragraph. This Privacy Policy was last updated on 9/1/2016 and is effective as of that date.

For customer assistance and general information, call our toll-free number: (800) 227-5767.   
Hours: Monday through Friday, 8:30 a.m. to 5 p.m. EST
